[{"id": "6000ecd09a72b906b34e3ce6", "question": "The adjective \"cutaneous\" relates to which part of the human body?", "answer": "Skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b031", "question": "Who was the last US president of the 19th century?", "answer": "William McKinley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5b", "question": "What rock band brought suit in 1994 claiming that Ticketmaster was an illegal monopoly?", "answer": "Pearl Jam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0e8f469bb8041d07a061", "question": "What is a word having same spelling but different sound and meaning?", "answer": "Heteronym", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef61876ce05a3942286e53", "question": "Which Hall of Fame British rocker is also an astrophysicist?", "answer": "Brian May", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a6", "question": "What is the alternative name for the \"Mona Lisa\"?", "answer": "La Gioconda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c144", "question": "What is another name for the sport of logrolling?", "answer": "Birling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a57", "question": "The 2006 Mel Gibson movie \"Apocalypto\" concerns the demise of what ancient empire?", "answer": "The Mayan Empire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58f", "question": "During which time period did the stegosaurus walk the earth?", "answer": "Late Jurassic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14f", "question": "What is the fear of the color purple called?", "answer": "Porphyrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d3a32596a59cbdfbd39c", "question": "What skyrocketed Apple to fame in 1984?", "answer": "A Superbowl ad", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb2f965ff7d326b622a7d", "question": "Which city was formerly called New Amsterdam?", "answer": "New York\u00a0City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c64", "question": "What Stephen King novel features an evil clown named Pennywise?", "answer": "It", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c077", "question": "Which English word is a combination of the first 2 letters of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "Alphabet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b316", "question": "On April 11, 1990, California Angel Mike Witt combined with which starter to pitch a no-hit victory?", "answer": "Mark Langston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0cc", "question": "What general led the Mexicans in the siege against the Alamo?", "answer": "Santa Ana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d13", "question": "What is Linus and Lucy's last name in \"Peanuts\" comics?", "answer": "Van Pelt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4f", "question": "During the 20th Century, in what year did the annexation of Austria by German take place?", "answer": "1938", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a79", "question": "What ethologist told the story of Elsa the lioness in the book \"Born Free\"?", "answer": "Joy Adamson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d0872596a59cbdfbd37d", "question": "Who said, \" I was really too honest a man to be a politician and live\u201d?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b53101dd7bf43be5e7cc", "question": "What is the name for the process of electing a Pope?", "answer": "Conclave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946b", "question": "What movie earned Katharine Hepburn her last Oscar?", "answer": "On Golden Pond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7690ceec85e375820b2ab", "question": "What structure links Detroit, Michigan, and Windsor, Ontario?", "answer": "Ambassador Bridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4d", "question": "In 1819, the US purchased Florida from what country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25f2e16682715b82711cee", "question": "With which sport would you associate Colin Montgomerie?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339726", "question": "How many fingers does Mickey Mouse have?", "answer": "8", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb0", "question": "Which was the first country to leave the Commonwealth in 1949?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4f", "question": "Who was the son of Zeus and Maia?", "answer": "Hermes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b502", "question": "What do you get when you mix champagne and stout?", "answer": "A Black Velvet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a087", "question": "Where are Rocket J. Squirrel and Bullwinkle Moose from?", "answer": "Frostbite Falls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f4684af848b908361b876", "question": "As of 2020, what is the highest grossing film of all time without taking inflation into account?", "answer": "Avengers: Endgame", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007810cbd51d85e222ab647", "question": "What art movement literally means the style of \"the wild beasts\"?", "answer": "Fauvism\u00a0(The movement emphasized vivid expressionism and unnatural use of color over representational or realistic values.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b934", "question": "What color is the 3 ball in pool?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1cdcd7bd84c0ea43ad42f", "question": "Skopje is the capital of which Eastern European country?", "answer": "Macedonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea45cdff048f679a45ab99", "question": "If nitrous oxide is added to an engine, what will the effect be?", "answer": "Adds more oxygen to the engine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b578", "question": "How many teaspoons are there in a cup?", "answer": "48", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6007821ebd51d85e222ab653", "question": "What was the original title of Auguste Rodin's famous sculpture \"The Thinker\"?", "answer": "Inspired by Dante's\u00a0\"Inferno,\"\u00a0\"The Thinker\" was originally entitled\u00a0\"The Poet\"\u00a0and conceived as a representation of Dante.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b142", "question": "What American won the Nobel Peace Prize in 2007?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0f", "question": "Who was the only woman to hold the title office in the \"Book of Judges\"?", "answer": "Deborah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bb35b4f2627b8fe95581beb", "question": "In ABC's \"Once Upon a Time\" what character was played by Colin O' Donoghue?", "answer": "Captain Hook", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a0bc20565ad31a57c79a", "question": "Who nicknamed New York City \"Gotham\"?", "answer": "Washington Irving", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beeb", "question": "What Is Joseph Cyril Bamfords claim to fame?", "answer": "Founded JCB", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c2e", "question": "What book series was written and illustrated by Jeff Kinney?", "answer": "Diary of a Wimpy Kid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a861", "question": "Which four countries share borders with Belgium?", "answer": "France, Germany, Netherlands and Luxembourg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d5c", "question": "What year was the first \"Twilight\" novel published in?", "answer": "2005", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17d", "question": "What is the opposite of an utopia?", "answer": "Dystopia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd43a7e83c707845b215a", "question": "What famous actor turned down the role of Trinity in film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Sandra Bullock turned down the role because she had the understanding that Will Smith was in the film.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef96e56ce05a3942286ea3", "question": "In the first televised baseball game, the Cincinnati Reds played what team?", "answer": "Brooklyn Dodgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901db26709c1c34536e6eb1", "question": "In what sport would a contestant perform a \"Fosberry Flop\"?", "answer": "High jump", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601370831381754895396382", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", the fictitious film that Kevin watches, \"Angels with Filthy Souls\", is a homage to what real film?", "answer": "\"Angels with Dirty Faces\" -- It is a 1938 gangster film starring James Cagney and Pat O'Brien.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bbba364247bf200fb8a6", "question": "What is the capital of Zambia?", "answer": "Lusaka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe699a420565ad31a57c749", "question": "What was the first probe to land on Venus?", "answer": "Venera 9", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc0a8ec223966ae8f885d", "question": "What guards the Ark of the Covenant in \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ae", "question": "In what city would you find Gorky Park?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea49b6ff048f679a45abba", "question": "Cephalgia is a medical term for what malady?", "answer": "Headache", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b019", "question": "Prior to Ronald Reagan, who was the last US president whose first and last name began with the same letter?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a02d6c0f9723ab15cb34", "question": "How many electoral college votes does a U.S. presidential candidate need to get elected?", "answer": "270", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f5", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Superfly\"?", "answer": "Curtis Mayfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af26", "question": "Which two armies fought in the Battle of Blood River?", "answer": "Boers and Zulus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a610", "question": "What is the world\u2019s most southerly capital city?", "answer": "Wellington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c9", "question": "What was Audrey Hepburn's real last name?", "answer": "Ruston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd8", "question": "In Arthurian legend, what was the name of King Arthur's magic sword?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a94720565ad31a57c800", "question": "What was the name of the outlaw gang in Tombstone, Arizona that was Wyatt Earp's arch enemy?", "answer": "Cochise County Cowboys", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c1", "question": "What country proclaimed the birth of its billionth citizen in 2000?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad9dd27e748bb36357acde0", "question": "After watching the movie \"Young Frankenstein\", what rocker was inspired to write a hit song?", "answer": "Steven Tyler (Walk this Way)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded065ea2747c8aff16d27", "question": "In which city would you find the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19d", "question": "What Palestinian Terrorist group infiltrated the 1972 Munich Olympics?", "answer": "Black September", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e6a3fe83fe1f2a824bd0", "question": "What was Mary Anning (1799\u20131847) famous for?", "answer": "Collecting fossil", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec8", "question": "Mr. Giles French was a character on which US TV show in the late 1960's?", "answer": "Family Affair", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c963", "question": "Parr, Smolt and Grilse are lifecycle stages for what fish?", "answer": "Salmon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e563fe83fe1f2a824bbc", "question": "The Islamic calendar is based on which cycle?", "answer": "Lunar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbe", "question": "What name was given to the leather protection cowboys wore over the front of their pants?", "answer": "Chaps", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af11", "question": "What \"trail\" did thousands of pioneers follow to Oregon during the 1800s?", "answer": "Oregon Trail", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe1eca1145fb29466707387", "question": "What does the Qantas airline name stand for?", "answer": "Queensland and Northern Territory Aerial Services", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf6", "question": "In which movie did Billie Burke portray a witch?", "answer": "The Wizard of Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015ec3dfe83fe1f2a824bfd", "question": "What artifact did Moses use to perform miracles and wonders in Egypt?", "answer": "A wooden staff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe522ce1bf59ab7d2e380eb", "question": "What is mistletoe for according to Polish folklore?", "answer": "Ward off evil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b276", "question": "How many soldiers are shown raising the flag over Iwo Jima in the famous photograph and statue?", "answer": "Six", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59675c4d2b59efe0e9417e94", "question": "What was Vince Gill\u2019s last #1 as a solo recording artist?", "answer": "Tryin\u2019 To Get over You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5bea5dad637d903c881c", "question": "Which country observes an official Vernal Equinox Day?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b947", "question": "Which sport did hall-of-famer Larry Bird play?", "answer": "Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b518", "question": "What is the pure spirit distilled from wine?", "answer": "Brandy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a0", "question": "In what state was the TV show \"B.J. and Bear\" set?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebe", "question": "Whose series of thirteen children's books of thirteen chapters each ended in 2006 with \"The End\"?", "answer": "Lemony Snicket's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab85", "question": "Who was the first person to reach the North Pole in 1909?", "answer": "Robert Peary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4c", "question": "In 1853, what country sold the US land, in what was known as the Gadsden Purchase?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c596", "question": "Blacked eyed peas are not peas, what are they?", "answer": "Beans", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a877", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Nevsky Prospekt\"?", "answer": "St. Petersburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be09", "question": "What NFL team replaced its AFL-era horse logo with a bolt of lightning?", "answer": "The San Diego Chargers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9c", "question": "Carlo Collodi created which famous children's character?", "answer": "Pinocchio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe36f230ada16518afdc047", "question": "What is the name of the Italian anise-flavored liqueur?", "answer": "Sambuca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a98c20565ad31a57c806", "question": "During World War II, what was the USS Indianapolis' secret mission?", "answer": "Delivering parts for the atomic bomb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a992", "question": "What river flows through Jackson Hole, Wyoming?", "answer": "The Snake River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339524", "question": "What movie character said the line \"Go ahead, make my day\"?", "answer": "Harry Callahan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b63", "question": "What were Robin Williams and Nathan Lane pretending to be in the movie \"The Birdcage\"?", "answer": "Straight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad34", "question": "Which company developed the A6M fighter plane known as \"Zero\" during WWII?", "answer": "Mitsubishi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f4", "question": "What was Maxwell Smart\u2019s agent number on \u201cGet Smart\u201d?", "answer": "86", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac5", "question": "What year was National Geographic magazine first published?", "answer": "1888", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96c7023c87fd04dd15e25", "question": "What instrument did Paul McCartney primarily play as a member of the Beatles?", "answer": "Bass", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b1745c3bb2d29f81593b703", "question": "In which capital city was the crime fighting organisation \"Interpol\" founded?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd660d6a5bfecdd737e0838", "question": "Who was the most Googled person of 2018?", "answer": "Meghan Markle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec5", "question": "Which Saint was murdered at Canterbury Cathedral in 1170?", "answer": "Thomas Beckett", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56b", "question": "What plant has a name from the French meaning \"lion's tooth\"?", "answer": "Dandelion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8b3bec223966ae8f8838", "question": "Prior to Brooks taking his life, what does he carve on the wall in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "\"Brooks was here.\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5661133a95c66dc4fe75e", "question": "Which British opera festival was started in 1934?", "answer": "Glyndebourne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d7c52596a59cbdfbd3ba", "question": "John Chapman was an amateur horticulturist better known under what name?", "answer": "Johnny Appleseed", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c817", "question": "What would a doctor call \"pes planus\"?", "answer": "Fallen arches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4afd49076251badbeabf", "question": "What was the first food to be intentionally microwaved?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e78fb24f84e0b9f9ffba", "question": "By what name was Milwaukee's Pettit National Ice Center known as until 1991?", "answer": "Wisconsin Olympic Ice Rink", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be580e25415ba52ed6f0aba", "question": "Which Canadian Prime Minister introduced the Maple Leaf national flag?", "answer": "Lester B. Pearson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b04c", "question": "The Treaty of Versailles officially ended what major war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67e", "question": "How many points must the victor score in a game of cribbage?", "answer": "61 or 121", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b5b", "question": "Which fairytale character slept for 20 years?", "answer": "Rip Van Winkle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b0ea45964118b2bb3809d1", "question": "What year did the \"ILOVEYOU\" virus began infecting computers worldwide?", "answer": "2000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd3c97e83c707845b2155", "question": "Which electronic musical instrument emits the eeriest of sounds and is the only instrument played without touching it?", "answer": "Theremin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a898", "question": "What city is home to the Telstra Tower?", "answer": "Canberra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69e5120565ad31a57c781", "question": "\"Night of Broken Glass\" was also called what?", "answer": "Kristallnacht", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad65", "question": "In 1701, who invented the seed-planting drill?", "answer": "Jethro Tull", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60137186138175489539638b", "question": "Who served as butler to the von Trapp family in \"The Sound of Music\"?", "answer": "Franz -- He spent several years as a loyal butler in the service of the Von Trapp family before he betrayed them to the Nazis.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f63", "question": "What actor blogs at \"Schrute-Space\" at NBC.com?", "answer": "Rainn Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b7", "question": "Which airship is featured on the cover of Led Zeppelin's debut album?", "answer": "Hindenburg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c6d1fbde8045e48466ba", "question": "What is the cause of Lyme disease?", "answer": "The bite of blacklegged ticks infected with Bacterium\u00a0Borrelia burgdorferi\u00a0or rarely, bacterium Borrelia mayonii.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea429eff048f679a45ab7b", "question": "What kind of animal is a chukar?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959c", "question": "Who plays the broken-hearted widower in the 2003 movie \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Liam Neeson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a331", "question": "Which cartoon character has a girlfriend named Petunia?", "answer": "Porky Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd5ec7e83c707845b2168", "question": "The musical score for Hitchcock's \"Psycho\" uses which instrument exclusively?", "answer": "Stringed instruments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c38b", "question": "What is the name for a human third molar?", "answer": "A wisdom tooth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aacb", "question": "Topeka is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a382", "question": "What is the capital of the Netherlands?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e95c97ccba3ffe45786e4", "question": "What alcohol do you mix with lemonade to make a Snowball cocktail?", "answer": "Advocaat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73572eec85e375820b24b", "question": "Who said, \"It\u2019s not enough that we do our best; sometimes we have to do what\u2019s required.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8c", "question": "Where was the Salvation Army's Christmas collection kettle first introduced?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8945ec223966ae8f8827", "question": "The tagline \"Justice has its price\" comes from which 1998 movie?", "answer": "\"A Civil Action\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6e88a9e54d890926f6c6", "question": "Which two islands makes up a commonwealth with Antigua?", "answer": "Barbuda and Redonda -- The three-island nation is in the Lesser Antilles.  Redondo is uninhabited and was formed from a volcano.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64e", "question": "What must a mole do every four hours so it doesn't die?", "answer": "Eat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd3", "question": "What century did Rembrandt live in?", "answer": "17th", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d0562596a59cbdfbd37a", "question": "Who said By all means marry. If you get a good wife you will become happy, and if you get a bad one you will become a philosopher?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008da4cf4f3bc4a292f8614", "question": "Where was the first commercial winery in the U.S.?", "answer": "Kentucky (Swiss vintner, John James Dufour, chose a spot along the Kentucky River for his vineyards and opened a winery in 1799.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde4966c6c6b019850c9a6f", "question": "Easter was named from what Anglo-Saxon goddess?", "answer": "Eostre", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a3", "question": "What were the surnames of Bonnie and Clyde?", "answer": "Parker and Barrow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca03", "question": "What natural events are ranked in severity by the Saffir Simpson scale?", "answer": "Hurricanes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338906", "question": "Who wrote the music for the stage version of \"Billy Elliot\"?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4d6", "question": "The Southern Ocean completely surrounds which continent?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8beeec223966ae8f8845", "question": "The protagonist in \"Grand Theft Auto: Vice City\" was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Ray Liotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c1", "question": "Which is the largest of the Canary Islands?\u00a0", "answer": "Tenerife", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8e", "question": "Who played the role of Colonel Kurtz in the movie \"Apocalypse Now\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69af420565ad31a57c758", "question": "What famous inventor proposed to his wife in Morse Code?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339284", "question": "What coach's team won the first challenge in season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Britney's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73e36eec85e375820b272", "question": "In \"Adventures of Huckleberry Finn\", who is Huck's father?", "answer": "Pap", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c7", "question": "What nationality was Rembrandt?", "answer": "Dutch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adfb", "question": "What year was the first Super Bowl played?", "answer": "1967", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc6f8ec223966ae8f8888", "question": "What time is usually displayed on the clock in Rick's garage in the animated series \"Rick and Morty\"?", "answer": "It is almost invariably at 2:00.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b2aa4fda37788a9a1dbc", "question": "Scotophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Darkness", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f7c9fe83fe1f2a824c26", "question": "Who was the UK\u2019s second woman Prime Minister?", "answer": "Theresa May", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75b", "question": "If you take a road trip to Hawaii, what road signs would you see?", "answer": "You can't drive to Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e32", "question": "Who is Joely Richardson's mother?", "answer": "Vanessa Redgrave", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acff", "question": "What building first appeared on the back of a $20 bill in 1928?", "answer": "The White House", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600244894be4723ccac221a5", "question": "Romanesque art prevailed during what time period?", "answer": "Romanesque art is the art of Europe from approximately 1000 AD to the rise of the Gothic style in the 13th century.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea43c6ff048f679a45ab88", "question": "What is the breakdown of a material by separation of the layers of which it is composed called?", "answer": "Delamination", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b55c", "question": "Depending on the story, which two fruits are often considered the Queen of Fruits?", "answer": "Mangos and Mangosteens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a826", "question": "What is the capital of Kenya?", "answer": "Nairobi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d470b0f8e329de4f877894", "question": "Who was the NBA's most valuable player in 1976, 1977 and 1980?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c5", "question": "In 1996 and 2000, who was the presidential nominee from the Green Party?", "answer": "Ralph Nader", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f6", "question": "What Beatles song begins with the opening fanfare from the French national anthem?", "answer": "All You Need is Love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33c", "question": "What is the name of Agrippa's husband, who she poisoned?", "answer": "Claudius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5954e8208e82ccaf3b9a67bb", "question": "Whose self-titled debut solo album spent the first of three weeks at #1 on Billboard\u2018s Country album chart?", "answer": "Wynonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988f", "question": "What is the name of the band with the members Jack Black and Kyle Gass?", "answer": "Tenacious D", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a127", "question": "Who said \"I always thought losing my virginity was a career move\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b18d", "question": "What year was astronaut Neil Armstrong born?", "answer": "1930", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cdc83e347d002c297e4e8", "question": "In 1973 Roland Ohisson was buried in a coffin made of what?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f73", "question": "In 1964, Michelangelo's Piet&#261; was on display at what major event?", "answer": "New York's World Fair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a7f64f6f5f79087132fb43", "question": "Which actress who played Alia Atreides in 1984's \"Dune\" and went on to star in 1998's \"Urban Legend\"?", "answer": "Alicia Witt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef63736ce05a3942286e64", "question": "Who was the first woman to host an American late night show?", "answer": "Joan Rivers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ea", "question": "What are the two most common coffee bean types?", "answer": "Arabica and Robusta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e8", "question": "The \"Robots in Disguise\" are better known as what?", "answer": "Transformers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963c", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Prince Philip?", "answer": "Princess Aurora's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601601a2fe83fe1f2a824c60", "question": "In what year were women first allowed to participate in the modern Olympic games?", "answer": "1900 -- in Paris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d70a2596a59cbdfbd3b1", "question": "Who invented corn flakes?", "answer": "Dr. John Harvey Kellogg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ca", "question": "Sir Frances Walshingham was what English monarch's \"spy-master\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth I's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb737c95e259d786908732c", "question": "Who was the Bolshevik leader that was exiled by Joseph Stalin after Vladimir Lenin\u2019s death?", "answer": "Leon Trotsky", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe37af80ada16518afdc05e", "question": "What action did the U.S. take along with Great Britain and Australia after Japan seized Indochina?", "answer": "They formed a trade embargo that cut off 90% of Japan's oil supply", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eaf", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"Witness for the Prosecution\"?", "answer": "Tyrone Power", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98b", "question": "What is added to Gin to make Pink Gin?", "answer": "Angostura Bitters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4dd5d06d333868d34d701", "question": "In which concentration camp did Anne Frank die?", "answer": "Bergen-Belsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b371", "question": "In World War II, where was the defensive line known as the \"Gin Drinkers Line\"?", "answer": "Hong Kong", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a438", "question": "In what country is the San Andreas Fault located?", "answer": "United States", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c857", "question": "What name is given to the full moon closest to the autumn equinox?", "answer": "Harvest moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b155", "question": "What year was Princess Diana born?", "answer": "1961", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffe4ab247818f5674af01ae", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"I am not afraid of storms, for I am learning how to sail my ship\u201d?", "answer": "\"Little Women\" (Amy March says this to Laurie about their marriage in the classic Louisa May Alcott novel.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa552bc73aa70ea0b70b22", "question": "The Black Forest is located in what European country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f8", "question": "What explorer disappeared in 1928 while on a rescue mission for survivors of the crashed airship \"Italia\"?", "answer": "Roald Amundsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db6", "question": "In what ominous numbered room is Winston Smith strapped to a chair at the end of \"Nineteen Eighty-Four\"?", "answer": "Room 101", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59029fe7cad1ec93f27df765", "question": "What country does the cappuccino originate from?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339207", "question": "What Scottish city is the setting for \"Trainspotting\" according to the plot?", "answer": "Edinburgh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008f0ecf842fa4c4ba96b7", "question": "What did William H. Seward buy from Russia in 1867?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace9", "question": "What Harvard dropout held 535 US patents upon his death in 1991, second only to Thomas Edison?", "answer": "Edwin Land", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b379", "question": "American Hamilton Smith patented what in 1858?", "answer": "A washing machine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba2c", "question": "Which US state's official flower is the Saguato Cactus?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfff4a1cf6db9ac4808d0d", "question": "Where did the Stonewall Riots take place?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a66a", "question": "Jefferson City is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e1", "question": "What river flows through Colorado's Black Canyon?", "answer": "Gunnison River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339200", "question": "What is the name of the White Stripes' drummer?", "answer": "Meg White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc1", "question": "What is a gricer interested in?", "answer": "Trains", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa5e36ce05a3942286ec5", "question": "What real American Revolution battle served as inspiration for the film \"The Patriot?\"", "answer": "The Battle of Cowpens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c713", "question": "Acrophobia is more commonly known as the fear of what?", "answer": "Heights", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b064", "question": "The \"CSS Hunley\" was the first of what type of vessel to sink an enemy ship?", "answer": "Submarine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b974", "question": "Which ice skater was attacked by one of her arch rivals?", "answer": "Nancy Kerrigan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e1", "question": "What Broadway musical featured \"The Telephone Hour\"?", "answer": "Bye Bye Birdie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a55e90aac110e4167073", "question": "To make beer, what is barley normally made into?", "answer": "Malt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90c", "question": "How many dots are there on a pair of dice?", "answer": "42", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0e12596a59cbdfbd382", "question": "Which country was the first to enact daylight savings time?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c434", "question": "What is a male cat if a female is a queen?", "answer": "Tom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea4892ff048f679a45abb0", "question": "How fast can an ostrich run?", "answer": "43 mph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87f", "question": "In what US city would you find the fashionable Dupont Circle neighborhood?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa38e9c73aa70ea0b70ad6", "question": "How many U.S. states are named after a President?", "answer": "One (Washington is named after George Washington, the first U.S. president.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd3e0ec223966ae8f88c9", "question": "Which superhero does Mark Watney emulate near the end of \"The Martian\"?", "answer": "Iron Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a83", "question": "Which original \"Star Trek\" character was played by James Doohan?", "answer": "Scotty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ed", "question": "Which US states end with the letter \"O\"?", "answer": "Colorado, Idaho, New Mexico and Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab99b6921a8909e5c332d2b", "question": "What year saw the release of the film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\"?", "answer": "1988", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf1", "question": "What hill in Athens does the Parthenon stand on?", "answer": "The Acropolis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee8", "question": "On what planet did the bottle city of Kandor originate?", "answer": "Krypton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339464", "question": "In what US town does the movie \"Groundhog Day\" take place?", "answer": "Punxutawney, PA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9da", "question": "If you suffer from Chirospasm what do you have?", "answer": "Writer's Cramp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa82", "question": "In which large bay would you find the Belcher Islands?", "answer": "Hudson Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7eb", "question": "What is the Latin name for the common mouse?", "answer": "Mus musculus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010c86e0775fa611bce67df", "question": "Voil\u00e0! translates to what?", "answer": "Here it is! or Here I am!", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21c", "question": "Traditional Scottish Highland Games feature which event where competitors throw a tapered 19 foot and 6 inch long log?", "answer": "Caber Toss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7493a9e54d890926f6fa", "question": "In Texas, it\u2019s illegal to swear in front of what?", "answer": "A corpse", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b3", "question": "The Winter Olympics Games were first held in which country?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f60b01dd7bf43be5e82e", "question": "What are Lay's potato chips known as in the U.K.?", "answer": "Walker's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a162b94f01ec323f849172a", "question": "What sport's periods are referred to as \"chukkas\"?", "answer": "Polo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dde", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"mammoth\"?", "answer": "Russian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a45", "question": "\"I'm So Glad We Had This Time Together\" was the closing theme song to what TV show?", "answer": "The Carol Burnett Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1de", "question": "Which members of the \"Bee Gees\" were twins?", "answer": "Maurice and Robin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338939", "question": "What annual celebration is taking place at the start of \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Christmas Eve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5902a14acad1ec93f27df775", "question": "In a Cortado, what is the main purpose of the milk?", "answer": "To reduce the acidity of the coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3de", "question": "When was Crazy Horse born?", "answer": "1842", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede34d6ce05a3942286dd1", "question": "Who was originally cast as Holly Golightly in \"Breakfast at Tiffany\u2019s\"?", "answer": "Marilyn Monroe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c258", "question": "In the computer world, what does the abbreviation CPU stand for?", "answer": "Central Processing Unit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab80", "question": "What country borders Sierra Leone to the north?", "answer": "Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb1", "question": "Which author wrote the novel \"The War of the End of the World\"?", "answer": "Mario Vargas Llosa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601debe96b1208747aa7e9d7", "question": "Which famous entrepreneur is credited with inventing the weekend?", "answer": "Henry Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b424", "question": "What year did Konrad Adenauer become the first Chancellor of West Germany?", "answer": "1949", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a01d", "question": "What actress was the narrator in the movie \"To Kill a Mockingbird\"?", "answer": "Kim Stanley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52b", "question": "What does the phrase Magna Cum Laude mean in English?", "answer": "With Great Honor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3233d5bf195a31e15d739f", "question": "What product changed its original name in the US from the \"Soundabout\"?", "answer": "Sony's Walkman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c69", "question": "What is the name of Tony Manero's dance partner in the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Stephanie Mangano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8e", "question": "Who was sued in 1999 by Rosa Parks after they used her name to title a hit song?", "answer": "OutKast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b752", "question": "Whose ear did Mike Tyson bite in a 1997 fight dubbed \"The Sound and the Fury\"?", "answer": "Evander Holyfield's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe526171bf59ab7d2e380f4", "question": "As of 2020, what was the top selling beer in the world?", "answer": "Snow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c932", "question": "What has superseded Newtonian mechanics of the atomic scale?", "answer": "Quantum mechanics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b0", "question": "What did the Lady of the Lake give King Arthur?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a1", "question": "Who Had A Hit In 1993 With \"She Don't Let Nobody\"?", "answer": "Chaka Demus & Pliers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfe009fb668d7dfe168b5c4", "question": "What English cricketer is nicknamed \"Beefy\"?", "answer": "Ian Botham", "category": "general"}]